meteogroup.com 2019-08-25

# Privacy Policy & Cookies | MeteoGroup

**Privacy Policy MeteoGroup Deutschland GmbH**

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy describes the information we collect about you as a user of our websites and mobile applications (“ **Site** ”) and our services, how this information is processed, and how you can opt out of certain types of processing.

  1. **Information about the responsible entity**

The entity responsible for the Site and our services is the MeteoGroup Deutschland GmbH (“MeteoGroup”), Am Studio 20a in 12489 Berlin, Germany, registered at Amtsgericht Berlin (Charlottenburg) HRB 67822.

For the website www.meteogroup.com MeteoGroup Limited (a UK registered company, company number 2665051), with registered offices at 292 Vauxhall Bridge Road, London, SW1V 1AE, United Kingdom, is the responsible entity.

This Privacy Policy applies on the same basis to each website referred to above.

  1. **What is personal information?**

Personal information means any information concerning the personal or material circumstances of an identified or identifiable individual (such as your name, address, telephone number, email address etc).

  1. **How do we process personal information?**

We collect personal information only as permitted by applicable data protection laws or with your consent. We may collect personal information from you when you visit the Site, use our services, complete registration or enquiry forms or send emails to us, so that we may provide you with the services and information which you request. Please do not submit your personal information to us if you do not wish us to collect it.

If you login or subscribe to any MeteoGroup or its affiliates service or product, we will use your personal information to provide you with the service or product you select, (e.g. personalising your services; sending you password reminders or notices about the relevant service or product being changed or suspended for emergency or routine maintenance).

If you purchase services and products from us we may also need your name, address and payment information in order to process your transaction.

  1. **Specific use of personal information regarding Mobile Applications (“Apps”)**

  1. 1 Location data during the use of Apps

Apps downloaded to your mobile phone or tablet may rely on location based services, such as your Global Positioning System ( **“GPS”** ) to inform you about forecasts regarding your current location automatically or upon demand. Such location-based functions are set by default. You may deactivate or reactivate these functions in the settings of your respective device.  Before or after installing the Apps – depending on your device – you will be asked whether you prefer to (de)activate these functions. We may only collect data regarding your location if you turn on such location services.

The data regarding your location will be anonymised after your forecast request. This anonymous data will be analysed to optimise our services as well as for marketing purposes. This does not identify your device or you. However, we may process your location data together with your personal information if you have given the appropriate consent.

Cookies are not used within Apps unless your browser is opened as part of the App. In this case, there may be cookies (details see below) on the device’s web browser.

4.2 Collection of personal information during the use of Apps

MeteoGroup collects any information you voluntarily chose to provide via the Apps as well as personal information if you register an account or purchase a Premium account where you are required to provide your email, password, user name and address to receive the respective services. We will collect the personal information to provide the service, to inform you about the service or other services by MeteoGroup or to ensure the processing and billing of the (Premium) account. The account will be activated via the App Store or the Play Store in compliance with their privacy policy. The users’ email addresses and device IDs are stored. This storage is for the purpose of authentication and enables you to use your account even in the event of a reinstallation of the programme or a change of device without having to register or purchase a new (Premium) account.  Additionally, the stored personal information is used for advertisements.

In addition to the foregoing, please note the following regarding our WeatherPro Premium App. To allow you to purchase this App, it is necessary for us to identify you. When you are using iOS, we can use the available Apple ID to do this. When you are using a version of Android, no Apple ID is available and we need to rely on other means to identify you. We do this by obtaining your e-mail address. For users with Android 8, we are able to only obtain the data point ‘e-mail address’ which we can then use for the identification purposes as set out. For users with Android 6 or 7 however, no separate data points are available. The data that can be obtained is divided into different groups of data points and access is provided per group. The data point ‘e-mail address’ is placed in the same group as the data point ‘contacts’. Therefore, by obtaining access to the group which contains the data point we need to identify you with and provide the WeatherPro Premium App to you, we technically obtain access to the contacts in your phone as well. We do not need access to your contacts and apart from having access to them, we do not process or store them.

Generally we will refrain from transferring your information to third parties that are not affiliated companies of the MeteoGroup. For exceptions see section “information sharing” below. Your personal information will be processed by third parties if it is necessary for the purpose of contract fulfilment, for the supply of the respective product or service, for the provision of further information or if you consented into such transferring of data. Such third parties’ places of business may be outside the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”). In such cases, we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be adequately protected. In addition, we will process personal information in an appropriate manner if we are legally obliged or entitled to disclose such information.

You may revoke your consent to process your personal information any time by contacting us. Please see Section 12 – Contact information below.

  1. 3 Use of Google Analytics during the use of Apps

For statistical analysis of our Apps we use Google Analytics. For details, see the respective section below. You can block the collection of the data related to your use of our Apps by Google in the App’s settings.

  1. 4 Use of Advertising ID tracking technology

We also collect information about your access to the Apps using Apple’s iOS IDentifier for Advertising (“ **IDFA** “) and the Google Advertising ID (“ **GAID** ”), which is technology similar to cookies.

This technology comprises pieces of software that include a unique reference code that store and sometimes tracks information about you. These can last only for the duration of your use of the Apps. Others are used to remember you when you return to the App and will last for longer.

We use these technologies to:

  * allow you to move around the Apps more quickly and easily;
  * remember your last login;
  * customise elements of the layout and/or content of the Apps for you;
  * collect anonymised, statistical information about how you use the Apps so that we can improve the Apps;
  * Gather information about your use of the Apps on a pseudonymous, no-name basis. This information is used to identify and place advertising which is believed to be relevant to you. 

You can opt-out of such tracking mechanisms at any time. If you would like to opt-out of technology we employ through our Apps, you may do so by blocking, deleting or disabling them as your device permits.

  1. 5 Use of crashlytics and Adjust2 during the use of Apps

Our Apps use the analysis tools crashlytics by Crashlytics, 1 Kendall Square, Cambridge, MA 02139, USA and Adjust2 by adjust GmbH, Saarbrücker Str. 36, 10405 Berlin, Germany.

These tools use anonymised IP addresses for analytical purposes. Thus, it is impossible to deduce who the particular person using the respective IP address is. Crashlytics provides us with analysis on system failures in real time and facilitates the system’s maintenance. You will find further information regarding crashlytics here: <http://try.crashlytics.com/terms>. You will find further information regarding Adjust2 here: [https://www.adjust.com](https://www.adjust.com/).

We may use additional analysis tools by other providers. If doing so, we will ensure that all data will be solely used in an anonymised way and the identification of a particular person will be impossible.

Every analysis tool can be deactivated at any time within the settings of the Apps.

  1. 6 Information sharing

We may disclose advertising IDs, user locations and aggregate statistics about users of the Apps to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, sponsors and other reputable third parties as well as for marketing and other lawful purposes; however, this data will include no personally identifiable information.

  1. **Use of cookies and similar technology**
    1. 1 General information

Cookies are small files stored by your browser software that identify your device to the cookie owner's server. Cookies help us to provide you with a better Site, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not, and by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. It also helps us to provide other services such as targetted advertisements. You can turn off cookies in your browser.

  1. 2 Types of cookies

There are two main types of cookies that we use: “Session” cookies – which only last for the duration of your browser session and expire when you close it and “Remember Me” cookies (also known as “Persistent” cookies) - cookies that remain on your computer after you close your browser and computer to remember you when you return to the Site.

  1. 3 Use of cookies by MeteoGroup

We use cookies to:

•           obtain statistical information about your general internet usage and learn how you and others use the Site, and to improve the Site and deliver a better service to you;

•           remember your session so that you can move from one page to another within the Site;

•          store your preferences; and

•           customise elements of layout and/or content of the Site for your preference and ease of use.

We do not use cookies to store your credit or debit card details.

  1. 4 Removal of cookies

You can remove cookies from your Browser. Most web browsers are set up to automatically accept cookies but, if you prefer, you may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting, you may be unable to use the full functionality of the Site and your user experience may be adversely affected. You can learn more about cookies by visiting www.allaboutcookies.org which includes additional information on cookies and how to block cookies using different types of browser.

A simple way of removing cookies may be to go to the “Tools” option in your web browser and select “Settings”. To delete all cookies on your computer to date, select “Clear Browsing History” and to set options for future cookies, select “Cookies” and the options you wish to apply to your web browser.

  1. 5 Our cookies in detail

The majority of the cookies used on the Site are used to record user preferences for repeat visitors and registered users. We use the following types of cookies on the Site (please note that the exact cookies used on the Site depend on services provided):

If you have a concern about a particular cookie, please contact us. Please see Section 12 – Contact information below.

5.6    Third party cookies  
Cookies are also set by third parties on the Site (such as Google Analytics, Google Maps and Google Ads) e.g. for advertising purposes or enhancement of the Site.

Examples of cookies set by Google Analytics:

We do not have access to these cookies.  We only allow them to be served. However, we may use the anonymised statistical information provided to us by Google Analytics arising from these third party cookies, for example, to monitor usage of the Site or improve the targeting of advertisements to users of the Site. You will find details about Google Analytics in the special section below.

The third parties that generate these cookies and action tags have their own privacy policies describing how they use information that they collect. More information about cookies placed by specific third parties and how to restrict or block their cookies can be accessed by following the link to their website and to generate an "opt-out" cookie that will stop any further cookies being written to your device. For instructions regarding the opt-out of Google services see www.google.com/policies/privacy/. You can also visit the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance (EDAA) website at <http://youronlinechoices.eu/> for information on how to obtain an "opt-out" cookie from other third parties.

**6.             Tools regarding statistical analysis of data used on Site**

6.1          Use of Google Analytics

The Site uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”), 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Google Analytics uses cookies, which – as explained above in detail – are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyse how our users use the Site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Site (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. In case of activation of the IP anonymisation, Google will truncate/anonymise the last octet of the IP address for Member States of the European Union as well as for other parties to the Agreement on the EEA. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is sent to and shortened by Google servers in the USA. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Site on our behalf, compiling reports on Site activity for us  and providing us with other services relating to Site activity and internet usage. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Site. Furthermore you can prevent Google’s collection and use of data (cookies and IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB>.

You can refuse the use of Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set on your computer, which prevents the future collection of your personal information when visiting the Site.  
Click here to opt-out of Google Analytics)

Further information concerning the terms and conditions of use and data privacy can be found at <https://www.google.de/intl/en_uk/policies/>. Please note that on the Site, Google Analytics code is supplemented by “anonymizeIp” to ensure an anonymized collection of IP addresses (so-called IP-masking).   

In addition, you can prevent the collection of the data generated by the cookie by Google, as well as the processing of this data by Google, by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available from the following link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

6.2          Use of the Scaleable Centralised Measuring System

Our services use the Scaleable Centralised Measuring System (‘Skalierbares Zentrales Messverfahren’ “SZM”) provided by the INFOnline GmbH ([https://www.infonline.de](https://www.infonline.de/)) to analyse statistical factors regarding the use of our services. 

SZM collects anonymised data and uses cookies with the identifier “ioam.de” or “ivwbox.de”, a LocalStorage object or a signature, which is generated by different information that are automatically transmitted by your browser. SZM measures the Site’s intensity of use and the number of its users. No individual user will be identified at any time. Your identity will always be protected. You will not receive any advertising via this measuring system.

You will find further information regarding SZM at [https://www.infonline.de](https://www.infonline.de/). You can opt out of the data processing by the SZM procedure via the following links: [http://optout.ioam.de](http://optout.ioam.de/) and [http://optout.ivwbox.de](http://optout.ivwbox.de/) .

6.3 Mouseflow

This website uses Mouseflow: a website analytics tool that provides session replay, heatmaps, funnels, form analytics, feedback campaigns, and similar features/functionality. Mouseflow may record your clicks, mouse movements, scrolling, form fills (keystrokes) in non-excluded fields, pages visited and content, time on site, browser, operating system, device type (desktop/tablet/phone), screen resolution, visitor type (first time/returning), referrer, anonymized IP address, location (city/country), language, and similar meta data. Mouseflow does not collect any information on pages where it is not installed, nor does it track or collect information outside your web browser. If you'd like to opt-out, you can do so at https://mouseflow.com/opt-out. If you'd like to obtain a copy of your data, make a correction, or have it erased, please contact us first or, as a secondary option, contact Mouseflow at privacy@mouseflow.com.

For more information, see Mouseflow’s Privacy Policy at http://mouseflow.com/privacy/.

For more information on Mouseflow and GDPR, visit https://mouseflow.com/gdpr/.

**7.             Social media plugins and data collection regarding the Site**

7.1          We have implemented Social Plugins from Social networks like Facebook, Twitter and Google+ (“Plugins”) so that you can share anything of interest to you with your friends and connections. See below.

7.2          Facebook

Our services use Plugins from Facebook Inc. (“Facebook”), 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA.

You may recognise Facebook Plugins via the Facebook logo, the “Like” button or the term “Facebook” on the Site. If you use our services, your browser not only connects to our server but also to Facebook’s servers. Thus, the content of the Plugin is transmitted to your browser which embeds content on the Site. Hence, Facebook receives information that you used our services. If you use our services while logged into your Facebook account, Facebook may be able to link use of our services to your Facebook account. E.g. if you click the “Like” button or post a Facebook comment this information may be transmitted directly to Facebook. We are not able to directly influence the amount of data which Facebook collects via the Plugin. Further information regarding data collected by Facebook may be found via the following link: <https://de-de.facebook.com/policy.php>.

7.3          Google+

Our services use Plugins from the social network Google+, operated by Google.

You may recognise references regarding the social network Google+ via use of the Google+ logo or “+1“ button. If you use our services, your browser not only connects to our server but also to Google’s servers. Thus, content of the Plugin is transmitted to your browser which embeds content on the Site. Hence, Google receives the information that you used our services. If you use our services while logged in with your Google+ account, Google may be able to link use of our services to your Google+ account. If you use functions of Google+ separately, this information may be transmitted directly to Google.

We are not able to directly influence the amount of data which Google collects via the Plugin. Further information regarding data collected by Google may be found via the following link: <http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy>.

7.4          Twitter

Furthermore we use the social network twitter (“Twitter”), operated by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103 USA.

You may recognise references regarding Twitter via use of the Twitter logo or the term “Twitter” on the Site. If you use our services, your browser not only connects to our server but also to Twitter Inc.’s servers. Thus, content of the Plugin is transmitted to your browser which embeds content on the Site. Hence, Twitter Inc. receives information that you used our service. If you use our services while logged in with your Twitter account, Twitter Inc. may be able to link use of our services to your Twitter account. If you use functions of Twitter separately, this information is transmitted directly to Twitter Inc.

We are not able to directly influence the amount of data which Twitter Inc. collects via the Plugin. Further information regarding data collected by Twitter Inc. may be found via the following link: <https://twitter.com/privacy>.

**8.             Advertisements on the Site and links to other websites**

The Site contains third party advertisements and links to other websites which are outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Please note that, if you access other websites using the links provided, the operators of these websites may collect (personal) information from you. This information will be used by them and will be subject to their privacy policy, which may differ from ours.

**9.             Advertisements in newsletters and emails by third parties**

MeteoGroup may send you emails or newsletters with information and offers about our platform and our other services. You can object to such communication at any time by contacting us using the contact details at the end of this Privacy Policy. To provide you with this information and these offers, MeteoGroup uses email addresses provided during a purchase on the Site or if you upgrade to a Premium account. These emails may be sent by our service processors. Your information may be transferred outside the EEA. If we transfer your information outside the EEA, we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected in an adequate way.

Third parties providing emails on behalf of MeteoGroup may statistically analyse this data

You may revoke a consent to use your email address at any time and we will remind you in every email we send you. We may cooperate with other third party providers of the above mentioned email or newsletter services to provide you with information about products, services and/or advertisements. In such cases we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected in an adequate way.

**10.             Storage of data and security**

Information that you submit via the Site is sent to and stored on our secure servers or in secure filing systems and your information is processed in accordance with European data protection laws. However, your information may be transferred to countries outside the EEA. By way of example, this may happen if one or more of our servers are from time to time located in a country outside the EEA or one of our service providers or group companies is located in a country outside the EEA. If we transfer your information outside the EEA in this way, we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected in an adequate way.

In addition, if you use our services while you are outside the EEA, your information may be transferred outside the EEA in order to provide you with those services.

Your stored personal information will be deleted if you revoke your consent, if storage of data is no longer necessary to serve its purpose or if storage is impossible due to other reasons (e.g. conflicting legal regulations).

The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. We will do our best to protect your personal information, but we cannot guarantee security of your data which you send to us via the internet.  Any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**11.             Accessing, rectifying, removing, blocking, restricting or revoking of personal information**

You may exercise any of the following rights by writing us or sending us an email (Please see Section 12 – Contact information below):

•           request access to your personal information, including the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal information concerned, and the recipients or categories of recipients to whom personal information is disclosed;

•           request proper rectification, removal, blocking or restriction of your personal information the processing of which does not comply with the provisions of applicable data protection law, in particular because of the incomplete or inaccurate nature of the personal information; 

•          revoke your consent to processing of your personal information at any time;

•           object at any time, out of legitimate and reasonable grounds in connection to your particular case, that your personal information shall be subject to processing;

·                      request to exercise your right to data portability; we will comply with your request as far as technically feasible.

Furthermore you may take legal action in relation to any potential breach of your rights regarding the processing of your personal information. You may also lodge complaints before the competent data protection supervisory authority.

You may request access to the personal information we hold about you (e.g. by providing you with a copy of this information), or request that we change and/or update the personal information we hold, by contacting us.

Upon request, we will give you access to the personal information held about you, unless specific limitations apply (e.g. if providing access would be unlawful).

We will respond to a request for access to personal information within a reasonable period after the request is made, and give access to the personal information in the manner requested by you, if it is reasonable and practicable to do so.

If we do not agree to provide you with access, or to amend your personal information as requested, you will be notified accordingly. Where appropriate, we will provide you with the reason/s for our decision, and the mechanisms available to complain about the refusal. If the rejection relates to a request to change your personal information, you may make a statement about the requested change and we will attach this to your record.

**12.             Contact information**

If you have any queries with regard to our data processing practices please contact your usual MeteoGroup contact or send us an email to privacy(at)meteogroup.com or write to us at MeteoGroup Deutschland GmbH, Datenschutzbeauftragter, Am Studio 20a, 12489 Berlin, Germany.
